Scott Savage

717-371-5808 | snsavage@gmail.com | GitHub: snsavage | Website: snsavage.com

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with a passion for cleanly written and well-tested code. With experience in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript, and a background in finance, I discovered programming while completing a Master's in Information Systems. I am thoughtful in my approach to web development and bring strong skills in data analysis that help companies turn data into actionable information.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

React Timer – Workout interval timer. (Live Demo: react-timer.snsavage.com)

- Developed single page application with React, React Router, Redux.
- Handled data persistence with custom Ruby on Rails API including JWT for authentication.
- Designed user-interface with Semantic UI.

Carb Tracker – Daily nutrition tracking to reach health goals. (Live Demo: carbtracker.herokuapp.com)

- Developed with Ruby on Rails, JavaScript and jQuery.
- Utilized NutritionIx API for natural language food searches.
- Tested codebase using RSpec, Capybara, and VCR.

Photo Vistas – *Unsplash.com photos as your browser homepage.* (Live Demo: <u>photovistas.com</u>)

- Developed with Sinatra using the MVC pattern including ActiveRecord ORM.
- Used unsplash rb gem to interface with the Unsplash API.
- Designed front-end with the Neat grid, Refills components, and custom SASS.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, SQL, Ruby, Sinatra, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Redux, TDD, Git, Vim

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

WeWork – New York, New York (Remote)

Flatiron School Teaching Assistant & Technical Coach – September 2017 – Present

- Assist students with programming questions including coaching on debugging and problem solving techniques.
- Conduct study groups on software development topics through live coding, tutorials, and open forums.

Aetna, Inc. – Harrisburg, Pennsylvania

Senior Project Lead / Financial Senior Associate / Financial Associate – October 2012 – November 2016

- Created and maintained financial and operations reports for multi-million dollar business divisions.
- Implemented new reporting methods and automated existing processes using Excel, Access, VBA.
- Advised operations team on IT projects to ensure effective communication and project success.

Susquehanna Bancshares, Inc. – Lancaster, Pennsylvania

Commercial Credit Analyst III / Commercial Credit Analyst II – September 2010 – September 2012

Conducted underwriting for Susquehanna Bank's Pennsylvania commercial loan portfolio.

Emerald Advisers, Inc. - Lancaster, Pennsylvania

Research Associate – September 2006 – September 2010

Performed investment research and financial analysis of publicly-traded companies.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Developer Program – September, 2017

• Flatiron School, New York, New York

Master of Science in Information Systems – May, 2015

• The Pennsylvania State University, Capital College, Middletown, Pennsylvania

Bachelor of Arts in Economics, Minor in Finance – May, 2006

• Millersville University of Pennsylvania, Millersville, Pennsylvania